transactions, including the completion of the Pickervation and Xcelergy acquisitions.
At the same time, we continue to invest in our internal R&D pipeline.
Up to date, Q2 has been a very positive year for us. We've had a very positive year for us.
We've had a very positive year for us. We've had a very positive year for us. We've had a very positive year for us.
Our capital distribution during the first half of this year, we paid out $9.1 billion in dividends
and repurchased $2.1 billion of shares under the current up to $10 billion share buyback program.
There is still $5.6 billion to be executed in this program, and we target to complete
the program by end of 2027, as previously indicated.
Slide 20, please.
With this, we are reaffirming our full year 2026 guidance. We continue to expect net sales to grow
low single-digit and core operating income to decline low single-digit for the full year.
For the full year 2026, we also continue to expect core net financial results to be around
$1.7 billion and core tax rate to be around 16.5%, both in line with our guidance from
beginning of the year. Moving to slide 21.
As I shared previously, H1 net sales declined 2% with a strong momentum of growth drivers delivering
performance at the upper end of sales guidance from the start of the year. Turning to H2,
we continue to expect net sales to grow mid-single-digit as we move beyond the impact
of U.S. generic erosion. However, it's worth pointing out that there will be a notable difference
in the sales growth rates between the two.
This is because we still have about $800 million of U.S. interest in the sales in previous
year Q3 base.
We expect H2 core operating income to grow mid-to-high single-digit with continued investment
in our growth drivers as well as our R&D pipeline.
Slide 22.
Slide 23.
Slide 24.
Slide 25.
Slide 26. Slide 27. Slide 28. Slide 29. Slide 30. Slide 30. Slide 31. Slide 32. Slide 32. Slide
31.
Slide 33. Slide 33. We expect a positive one percentage
point impact on full-year net sales and a positive one percentage point impact on
core operating income.
Slide 34.
Slide 37.
Slide 38.
Slide 40.
Slide 35.
Slide 44.
Slide 45.